Sergey Todyshev

- email: stodyshev@gmail.com
- · skype: sergey.todyshev
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/sergeytodyshev
- https://github.com/sergeyt

Summary

I am a software engineer with 15 years of experience specializing in any kind of programming. I like writing elegant and efficient code, solving challenging tasks, learning new technologies and programming tools. I have two beautiful kids and two funny cats.

Operating Systems

- Linux (Debian, Ubuntu)
- · Microsoft Windows
- Mac OS X

Programming Languages

I am polyglot and can easily adopt to new language, but in these languages I have enough experience to be productive from first working days: C#, Java, JavaScript, Python, BASH, C/C++

Work Experience

2016 - present, Full Stack Engineer, Xored

I was working as Full Stack developer on Spirent Velocity automation platform. This is a very complex project having a huge frontend implemented in React. Historically alt.js was selected as classical implementation of Flux approach and primary solution for state management. Since 2017 I've initiated integration of Redux as replacement of legacy alt.js. And now we are happily migrating to Redux.

Keywords: Linux, Java, JavaScript, React, Redux, Flux, Golang, Python, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Docker, OpenStack

2007 - 2016, Full Stack Engineer, DataWorks

I was being a part of super dev team that working on development of huge reporting system called Active Reports. Here I've made a significant contribution rewriting report engine that dramatically boosts performance of the engine. Also contributed to development of ActiveReports Server.

Here we even crafted a binary cross-compiler from .NET byte-code to Adobe Flash Player byte-code just to implement Active Reports Flash Viewer and this viewer was popular some time:) I was primary author of this cross-compiler coding major part of it.

Keywords: .NET, C#, JavaScript, RDL, Reporting, Data Retrieving and Processing, Windows, IIS

2002 - 2007, Software Engineer, IAE

Here as PhD student I've implemented hardware abstraction layer to control multiple devices of Circle Laser Writing System created and designed by IAE. This module allows creation of multiple device configurations, then you can easily load given configuration at runtime without recompilation of control program. This significantly reduced time and cost on testing all laboratory devices and debugging of control program on configurations with device emulators.

Keywords: C++, C#, Windows Driver Clients, Computed Aided Tomography, Software for Interferometer & Profilometer Devices

Education

- 1999 2004, Novosibirsk State University, Faculty of Information Technologies. Specialty: Computers, Complexes, Systems and Networks
- 2004 2007, Institute of Automation and Electrometry, PhD student

References

- Scott Willeke Manager at GrapeCity (currently Technical Product Manager at Smartsheet), Greater Seattle Area, WA, USA
- Issam Elbaytam Chief Software Architect at GrapeCity, Raleigh, NC, USA
- Yuriy Kashnikov VP of Engineering at Xored Software, Novosibirsk, Russia